Abhijeet Pradhanang

Full-stack developer | Software Engineer

abhipradhanang@gmail.com +9779840020253 | Website | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Experience in frameworks like **Node.js**, **Nest.js**, **Vue.js**, **Nuxt.js**, **React.js**, **Typescript**, **Laravel**, **Semantic HTML**, **CSS3/Sass**, **AWS S3**, **AWS SQS**, **AWS SNS**. Responsible for developing technical documents and **roadmaps** by communicating with the stakeholder on a regular basis and **agile** (**Scrum**) development practitioner. Experience with developing the backend for web (SPA) and mobile applications. Responsible for the improvement of system design adhering to the **SOLID** principles as well as leading a team of developers and mentoring juniors.

EXPERIENCE

Codeware Lab Pvt. Ltd., Kathmandu, Nepal | Dec 2022 - present Senior Software Engineer

- Drive the development of admin applications for Shopify using Nest.js and React.js.
- Responsible for deploying applications through Heroku.
- Implemented csv imports for bulk resource imports.
- Design NoSQL database with MongoDB and Mongoose.

Gurzu Inc, Lalitpur, Nepal | Jan 2022 - Dec 2022 **Software Engineer**

- Developed admin application for e-commerce using Shopify, Node.js
 (Nest.js), Typescript, React.js, MongoDB, AWS SQS, AWS SES, and AWS SNS.
- Designed NoSQL database with MongoDB.
- Implementation of **AWS SNS** for updating the store inventory through the notification service, **AWS SQS** for queuing webhooks sent by Shopify event bridge, and **AWS SES** for sending emails.
- Preparation of technical design documents with the proposed changes required to satisfy new business requirements along with conducting stand-up meetings.
- Implementation of **Bull Queue** to run background job queues.

- Implementation of the front end of admin apps using **Shopify Polaris**.
- Handle, develop, and maintain multiple Shopify projects.

Dzango, Hong Kong | Oct 2017 - Dec 2021

Software Engineer & Team Lead

- Developing corporate applications using Nest.js/Nuxt.js/Rest API, Typescript, Laravel/Vue.js/GraphQL, MySQL, and Docker with Gitlab CI for CI/CD in AWS server and Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
- Integration with payment gateways like PayPal, Omise along with Xero,
 Google Calendar API, and AWS S3 buckets for storage.
- Practiced TDD (Test Driven Development) using Jest, Cypress, and PHPUnit.
- Developed mobile application using the same codebase as web using
 Cordova for android and iPhone.
- Designed front-end applications from UI/UX tools like AdobeXD, Invision, and Figma using BEM (Block-Element-Modifier) styling convention.
- Implementation of security layers to verify the source of the request and use of webhooks as well.
- Designed **micro-service architecture** which includes auth server and content management system.
- Implementation of **Socket.io** used to build a chatting box.

FREELANCE PROJECTS

Dimitra, Canada

Full-stack developer | Software Engineer

- Developed backend for the product Connected Farmer, Connected Coffee using Node.js, and Livestock Guru using Nest.js.
- Worked with **GraphQL Federation Gateway** to implement the micro-service architecture in Livestock Guru.
- Consumed Google Spreadsheet API to seed the data into the database.
- Documented APIs using Swagger docs.
- Implemented push notifications using **Firebase**.
- Communicated with designers and SMEs to understand and remove ambiguity in feature requests.
- Tech stacks: Nest.js with GraphQL, Node.js, Vue.js, MySQL, Sequelize for ORM, Google API, Firebase

SBAC, Thailand

- An online English training application, which was created for a Thai University (SBAC).
- Responsible to talk with the client to understand the requirements and design flowcharts and timeframe for the application.
- Compression and optimization of images and application bundle.
- Implemented three main features of the application:
 - One-to-one conversation using own instance of **Jitsi.meet**, which involved booking, approval, cancellation, and reminding the meetings.
 - Online courses, which are created by the teachers of SBAC. It involves texts, embedded links, videos, and documents that can be uploaded.
 - Test, which includes recording audio, writing, and multiple choices.
- Responsible for implementing recording of meetings using JS Web API to combine two streams of audio and video of both the users and storing the recording in an S3 bucket.
- Implemented feedback system from the users on the corresponding party after the completion of the meeting.
- Report generation of each student to display the marks obtained.
- Responsible for deploying using **Docker via GitLab ci**.

AEDCAAN, Nepal

- An admin application for the report and budget management for the Aerodrome Engineering Department of Nepal; created using Laravel and Vue.js
- Report generation in a spreadsheet according to the project, location, or date.
- Implemented spreadsheet download according to the geographical order of the project's location (east-west or west-east, user can select).
- Deployment using CPanel and created subdomains for the project.
- Eager/lazy load the data from the database to improve query performance.

4CLOVER NEPAL

- Inventory management system for a single vendor with a recorded history of past purchases and sales.
- Implemented using **Node.js** for backend and **React.js** for front-end.
- Authentication using Firebase authentication.
- Summary of cash flow according to month.

PROJECTS

- Flagship | Multi merchant Shopify projects | Nest.js, React.js, MongoDB,
 AWS SQS, AWS SNS, AWS SES, Shopify
- <u>Dimitra</u> | Platform for farmers regarding crops and livestocks | Node.js,
 Nest.js, Vue.js, Vuetify, GraphQL, Microservice with Federation Gateway
- Plizz | Xero Asia Partner of the Year 2021 | Accounting web application in Thailand | Nest.js, Nuxt.js, MySQL, GCP, TypeORM, Firebase
- <u>Belaws</u> | Expansion to 4 countries | Corporate service application | Laravel,
 Vue.js, MySQL, AWS S3, Docker
- SBAC | 5k users | Online English teaching web application for Thailand
 University | Freelance | Laravel, Vue.js, MySQL, AWS S3, Docker, Jitsi.meet
- Polifonic | Wiki application | Micro-service architecture | Laravel, Node.js,
 Vue.js, MySQL, MongoDB
- 4Clover Nepal | Inventory management for a local business | Node.js, React.js, Firebase
- <u>AEDCAAN</u> | Nepal Government aviation budgeting application | Freelance |
 Laravel, Vue.js
- <u>Kudomoments</u> | Online group card application | Freelance | Node.js, Nuxt.js,
 Digital Ocean space
- DzangoHQ | Employee management system | In house project | Laravel,
 Vue.js
- CollectivFood | London-based food supply application | Laravel, Vue.js, Cordova

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelors in Computer Engineering

- Kathmandu Engineering College, Kalimati, Kathmandu (2013 - 2017)

+2 in Physics

- St. Xaviers' College, Maitighar, Kathmandu (2011 - 2013)

School education

- Little Angels' School, Hattiban, Lalitpur

Business English Communication (Nov 2020 - Dec 2021)